Stephen E. Malawista papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Submission of manuscripts for publication, Series IV
  - Manuscripts eventually published, Subseries 1
    - 1980s
      - Articles 79, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        Malawista, S.E., Steere, Allen C. and Hardin, John A. "Lyme disease: a unique human model for an infectious etiology of rheumatic disease," Yale J. Biol. Med. 57: 473-477, l984.
        Correspondence, 1984, reviewer's comments, drafts, and typed notes of two discussions from the First International Symposium on Lyme Disease, November, 1983. On the symposium, see Box 59, Folder 8.
      - Articles 80, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        Hardin, John A., Steere, Allen C., and Malawista, S.E. "The pathogenesis of arthritis in Lyme disease: Humoral immune responses and the role of intra-articular immune complexes," Yale J. Biol. Med. 57: 589-593, l984.
        Letter, 1984, and draft.
      - Articles 81, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        Malawista, S.E., Van Blaricom, G. and Cretella, S.B. "Cytokineplasts from human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes: Lack of oxidase activity and extended functional longevity," Inflammation 9: 99-l06, l985.
      - Articles 82, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
        Johnston, Y.E., Duray, P.H., Steere, A.C., Kashgarian, M., Buza, J., Malawista, S.E. and Askenase, P.W. "Lyme arthritis: spirochetes found in synovial microangiopathic lesions," Am. J. Path. ll8: 26-34, l985.
        Copy of draft with Malawista's changes.
      - Articles 83, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 12)
        Steere, A.C., Green, Jerry, Schoen, Robert T., Taylor, Elise, Hutchinson, Gordon J., Rahn, Daniel W. and Malawista, S.E. "Successful parenteral antibiotic therapy of established Lyme arthritis," New Engl. J. Med. 3l2: 869-874, l985.
        Note from Allen Steere and drafts under the title "Curing Lyme Arthritis: Successful Antibiotic Therapy of Established Joint Involvement."
      - Articles 84, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        Dyett, Deborah E., Malawista, S.E., Van Blaricom, G., Melnick, D.A. and Malech, H.L. "Functional integrity of cytokineplasts: specific chemotactic and capping responses," J. Immunol. l35: 2090-2094, l985.
        Correspondence, 1985, drafts.
      - Articles 85, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E., Duff, G.W., Atkins, E., Cheung, H.S. and McCarty, D.J. "Crystal-induced endogenous pyrogen production: a further look at gouty inflammation," Arthritis Rheum. 28: 1039-1046, 1985.
        Correspondence, 1984-1985, drafts, photographs.
      - Articles 86, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        Dyett, Deborah E., Malawista, S.E., Naccache, P.H. and Sha'afi, R.I. "Stimulated cytokineplasts from human polymorphonuclear leukocytes mobilize calcium and polymerize actin," J. Clin. Invest. 77: 34-37, 1986.
        Correspondence, 1985, drafts. The manuscript was first submitted to and rejected by Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications.
      - Articles 87, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E., and Van Blaricom, Gretchen. "Phagocytic capacity of cytokineplasts from human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes," Blood Cells 12: 167-173, l986.
        Correspondence, 1986, commentary by Dr. Katherine Przswansky, Malawista's reply, and drafts.
      - Articles 88, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E. "Microtubule function in human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes: analysis through heat-induced lesions," in: Dynamic Aspects of Microtubule Biology, Proc. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 466: 858-866, l986.
        Correspondence, 1984-1986, notes, drafts, and program and abstracts for the "Conference on Dynamic Aspects of Microtubule Biology," held by the New York Academy of Sciences, December 3-6, 1984.
      - Articles 89a, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E., and Van Blaricom, G. "Cytoplasts made from human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes with or without heat: preservation of both motile function and respiratory burst oxidase activity," Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 84: 454-458, 1987.
        Correspondence, reviewers' comments, drafts.
      - Articles 89b, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        Continuation of previous folder.
      - Articles 90, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        Di Giovine, F.S., Malawista, S.E., Nuki, G., and Duff, G.W. 'Interleukin 1 (IL 1) as a mediator of crystal arthritis: Stimulation of T cell and synovial fibroblast mitogenesis by urate crystal-induced IL 1," J. Immunol. 138: 3213-3218, 1987.
        Correspondence, 1985-1986, reviewers' comments, drafts. The paper was "not acceptable in its present form," and had to be revised.
      - Articles 91, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        MacWorth-Young, C.G., Harris, E.N., Steere, A.C., Rizvi, F., Malawista, S.E., Hughes, G.R.V. and Gharavi, A.E. "Anti-cardiolipin antibodies in Lyme disease," Arthritis Rheum. 31:1052-1056, l988.
        Letter from Charles Macworth-Young, first author, to co-authors, 1988, asking for their signatures for copyright transfer.
      - Articles 92, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        Okamura, Naoki. Malawista, S.E., Roberts, Robert L., Rosen, Henry, Ochs, Hans D., Babior, Bernard M., and Curnutte, John T. "Phosphorylation of the oxidase-related 48K phosphoprotein family in the unusual autosomal cytochrome-negative and X-linked cytochrome-positive types of chronic granulomatous disease." Blood 72: 811-816, l988.
        Correspondence, 1987-1988, resubmission with response to reviewers, drafts.
      - Articles 93, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E., Van Blaricom, G., and Breitenstein, M.G. "Cryopreservable neutrophil surrogates: Stored cytoplasts from human polymorphonuclear leukocytes retain chemotactic, phagocytic, and microbicidal function," J. Clin. Invest. 83: 728-732, 1989.
        Correspondence, 1988, drafts, notes, photographs of graphs.
        See Box 81, Folder 1 for more notes.
      - Articles 94, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        Malawista S.E., Van Damme, J., Sipe, J.D., Duff, G.W., and Weiss, M.C. "Independent effects of Interleukin 6 (IL-6) and Interleukin 1 (IL-1) on accumulation of specific m-RNA for fibrinogen and for serum amyloid A in human hepatoma (HepG2) cells," Proc. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 557:518-520, 1989.
        Drafts, photographs.
    - 1990s
      - Articles 95, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        Persing, D.H., Telford, S.R. III, Rys, P.N., Dodge, D.E., White, T.J., Malawista, S.E. and Spielman, A. "Detection of Borrelia burgdorferi DNA in museum specimens of Ixodes dammini ticks," Science 249:1420-1423, 1990.
        Correspondence, 1990, reviewers' comments, drafts.
      - Articles 96, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. and de Boisfleury-Chevance, A. J. Leuk. Biol. 50:313-315, 1991.
        "Cryopreserved cytoplasts from human polymorphonuclear leukocytes (cytokineplasts) are chemotactic at speeds comparable to those of fresh intact cells."
        Correspondence 1991, drafts, and photographs.
      - Articles 97, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        Rahn, D.W. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease: Recommendations for diagnosis and treatment," Ann. Int. Med. 114: 472-481, 1991.
        Correspondence, 1990, comments of reviewer, drafts.
      - Articles 98, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E., Trock, D. and Edelson, R. "Treatment of rheumatoid arthritis by extracorporeal photochemotherapy: a pilot study," Arthritis Rheum. 34:646-654, 1991.
        Correspondence 1990-1991, reviews, drafts.
      - Articles 99, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        Huang, A.J., Silverstein, S.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Cryopreserved cytoplasts from human neutrophils migrate across monolayers of human endothelial cells." J. Leuk. Biol. 50:624-627, 1991.
        Correspondence 1991, drafts, photographs.
      - Articles 100, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        di Giovine, F., Malawista, S.E., Thornton, E. and Duff, G., "Urate crystals stimulate production of tumor necrosis factor alpha from human blood monocytes and synovial cells: Cytokine mRNA and protein kinetics, and cellular distribution," J. Clin. Invest. 87:1375-1381,1991.
      - Articles 101, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        Fatehnejad, S., Fikrig, M.K., Rahn, D.W., and Malawista, S.E. "Parvovirus arthritis mistaken for Lyme arthritis," J. Rheum. 19:1002-1003, 1992.
      - Articles 102, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        Malawista, S.E., Schoen, R.T., Moore, T.L., Dodge, D.E., White, T.J., and Persing, D.H. "Failure of multitarget detection of Borrelia Burgdorferi-associated DNA sequences in synovial fluids of patients with juvenile rheumatoid arthritis: A cautionary note." Arthritis Rheum. 35:246-247, 1992.
        Correspondence 1990, 1991.
      - Articles 103, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        Persing, D.H., Barthold, S.W. and Malawista, S.E. "Molecular detection of Borrelia burgdorferi." In: Lyme Disease: Molecular and Immunologic Approaches, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, pp. 299-315, 1992.
      - Articles 104, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        Erickson, R.W., Malawista, S.E., Garret, M., Van Blaricom, G., Leto, T. and Curnutte, J.T. "Identification of a thermolabile component of the human neutrophil NADPH oxidase: a model for chronic granulomatous disease caused by deficiency of the p67-phox cytosolic factor," J. Clin. Invest. 89:1587-1595, 1992.
        Reviewer comments and replies, correspondence 1990, 1991.
      - Articles 105, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        Smallwood, J.I. and Malawista, S.E. "Protein kinase C isoforms in human neutrophil cytoplasts," J. Leuk. Biol. 51:84-92, 1992.
      - Articles 106a, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        Malawista S.E., Montgomery R.R., van Blaricom G. "Evidence for reactive nitrogen intermediates in killing of staphylococci by human neutrophil cytoplasts: A new microbicidal pathway for polymorphonuclear leukocytes." J Clin Invest. 1992 Aug;90(2):631-6.
        Rejected by Science, accepted with revisions by the Journal of Clinical Investigation.
        Correspondence 1992
      - Articles 106b, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Articles 107, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. "The American College of Rheumatology: Evolution through planning (Presidential Address)," Arthritis Rheum. 36:433-438, l993. Folder contains data on American College of Rheumatology and correspondence 1992.
      - Articles 108a, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        Maridonneau-Parini, I., Malawista, S.E., Stubbe, H., Russo-Marie, F., Polla, B.S. "Heat shock in human neutrophils: Superoxide generation is inhibited by a mechanism distinct from heat-denaturation of NADPH oxidase and is protected by heat shock proteins in thermotolerant cells," J. Cell. Physiol. 156: 204-211, 1993.
        Folder contains drafts and Malawista's correspondence with Isabelle Maridonneau-Parini, Institut Pasteur, 1988-1992.
      - Articles 108b, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Articles 109, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        Wallach, F.R., Forni, A.L., Hariprashad, J., Stoeckle, M.Y., Steinberg, C.R., Fisher, L., Malawista, S.E. and Murray, H.W "Circulating Borrelia burgdorferi in patients with acute Lyme disease: Results of blood cultures and serum DNA analysis," J. Infect. Dis. 168: 1541-1543, 1993.
      - Articles 110, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        Cooper, J.D., Schoen, R.T., and Malawista, S.E. "Treatment of asymptomatic, retrospectively diagnosed Lyme disease" (letter), Arthritis Rheum. 36:1637-1638, l993.
      - Articles 111, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        Smallwood, J.I., Malawista, S.E. "Colchicine, crystals and neutrophil tyrosine phosphorylation," Editorial, J. Clin. Invest. 92:1602-1603, 1993.
      - Articles 112, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        Montgomery, R.R., Nathanson, M.H., and Malawista, S.E. "The fate of Borrelia burgdorferi, the agent for Lyme disease, in mouse macrophages: Destruction, survival, recovery," J. Immunol. 150:909-915, 1993.
      - Articles 113, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        Rahn, D.W. and Malawista, S.E. "Treatment of Lyme Disease (Special Article)," in: 1994 Year Book of Medicine. Mandell, G.L., Bone, R.C., Cline, M.J., O'Rourke, R.A., Greenberger, N.J., Utiger, R.D., Epstein, F.H. and Malawista, S.E. eds. Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, 1994, pp. xxi-xxxvi.
      - Articles 114, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        Persing, D.H., Rutledge, B.J., Rys, P.N., Podzorski, D.S., Reed, K.R. Mitchell, P.N., Liu, B., Fikrig, E. and Malawista, S.E. "Target imbalance: Disparity of Borrelia burgdorferi genetic material in synovial fluid from Lyme arthritis patients," J. Infect. Dis. 169:664-668, 1994.
        Correspondence 1993, photographs.
      - Articles 115, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        Di Caudo, D.J., Su, W.P.D., Marshall, W.F., Malawista, S.E., Barthold, S.W., and Persing, D.H. "Acrodermatitis chronica atrophicans in the United States: Clinical and histopathologic features of six cases," Cutis 54:81-84, 1994.
      - Articles 117, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 4)
        Montgomery, R.R., Nathanson, M.H., and Malawista, S.E. "Fc and non-Fc mediated phagocytosis of Borrelia burgdorferi by macrophages," J. Infect. Dis. 170:890-893, 1994.
      - Articles 118, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        Rollet, E., Caon, A.C., Roberge, C.J., Liao, N.W., Malawista, S.E., McColl, S.R. and Naccache, P.H. "Tyrosine phosphorylation in activated human neutrophils: Comparison of the effects of different classes of agonists and identification of the signalling pathways involved," J. Immunol. 153:253-363, 1994.
      - Articles 119, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        Newburger, P.E., Malawista, S.E., Dinauer, M.C., Gelbart, T., Woodman, R.C., Chada, S., Shen, Q., Orkin, S.H., Quie, P.G., and Curnutte, J.T. "Chronic granulomatous disease due to glutathione peroxidase deficiency, revisited," Blood 84:3861-3869, 1994.
        Originally sent to NEJM. Includes drafts of earlier related articles, 1986-1987.
        Correspondence 1993, 1994, drafts of earlier version (1986- 1987).
      - Articles 121, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        Malawista, S.E., Barthold, S.W., and Persing, D.H. "Fate of Borrelia burgdorferi DNA in tissues of infected mice after antibiotic treatment," J. Infect. Dis. 170:1312-1316, 1994.
        The manuscript was previously sent to the Journal of Clinical Investigation and rejected.
        The folder also contains a letter by Dr. Gary P. Wormser commenting on the article submitted to Journal of Infectious Diseases and a letter to the Editor by Malawista, Barthold, and Persing in response, published in the journal 171 (1995): 1380.
      - Articles 122, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        Stein, D.K., Malawista, S.E., Van Blaricom, G., Wysong, D., and Diamond, R.D. "Cytoplasts generate oxidants but require added neutrophil granule constituents for fungicidal activity against Candida albicans hyphae," J. Infect. Dis. 172:511-520, 1995.
      - Articles 123, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        Fikrig,E., Liu, B., Fu, L.L., Das, S., Smallwood, J.I., Flavell, R.A., Persing, D.H., Schoen, R.T., Barthold, S.W., and Malawista, S.E. "An ospA frame shift, identified from DNA in Lyme arthritis synovial fluid, results in an Osp that does not bind protective antibodies," J. Immunol. 155:5700-5704, 1995.
      - Articles 129, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        Smallwood, J.I., and Malawista, S.E. "An apparently novel protein of human leukocytes, reactive with an antibody to protein kinase C-gamma, is rapidly modified upon cell activation: Initial characterization in neutrophils and their cytoplasts," Inflammation 22:1-28, 1998.
        Previously sent to Journal of Leukocyte Biology and rejected.
      - Articles 130, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        Malawista, S.E., and de Boisfleury Chevance, A. "Random locomotion and chemotaxis of human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes in the presence of EDTA: PMN in close quarters require neither leukocyte integrins nor external divalent cations," Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 94:11577-11582, 1997.
      - Articles 132, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        Smallwood, J.I., and Malawista, S.E. "Analysis of the PKC-y-related immunocrossreactive region of a novel neutrophil protein, y-rp," Inflammation 23:387-410, 1999.
    - 2000s
      - Articles 133 (Restricted), 2000 (Box 31, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E., Montgomery, R.R., Wang, X.M., Fu, L.L., and Giles, S.S., "Geographic clustering of an Osp A mutant of B. burgdorferi. Possible implications of multiple variants for Lyme disease persistence," Rheumatology 39:537-541, 2000.
        Previously sent to Journal of Infectious Diseases.
        Folder contains patient names and may be restricted.
      - Articles 134, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 3)
        Montgomery, R.R., Palmarozza, R.E., Beck, D.S., Ngo, E., Joiner, K.A., and Malawista, S.E. "Functional competence of peritoneal macrophages in murine Lyme borreliosis," Inflammation 24:277-288, 2000.
        Previously sent to Infection and Immunity which rejected it.
      - Articles 135, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. "Resolution of Lyme arthritis, acute or prolonged: A new look." (Opinion) Inflammation 24:493-503, 2000.
      - Articles 136a, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E., de Boisfleury Chevance, A., and Boxer, L.A. "Random locomotion and chemotaxis of human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes from a patient with Leukocyte Adhesion Deficiency-1: Normal displacement in close quarters via chimneying," Cell Motil. Cytoskel. 46:183-189, 2000.
        The manuscript was first sent to Blood, and revised at least twice.
      - Articles 136b, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Articles 138, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        Akkoyunlu, M., Malawista, S.E., Anguita, J., and Fikrig E., "Exploitation of IL-8-induced neutrophil chemotaxis by the agent of human granulocytic ehrlichiosis," Infection & Immunity 69:5577-5588, 2001.
        First sent to Immunology.
      - Articles 139, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        Montgomery, R.R., Wang, X.-M., and Malawista, S.E. "Murine Lyme disease: No evidence for active immune downregulation in resolving or subclinical infection." J. Infect. Dis. 183: 1631-1637, 2001.
      - Articles 144a, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E., Van Damme, J., Smallwood, J.I., and de Boisfleury Chevance, A. "Chemotactic activity of human blood leukocytes in plasma treated with EDTA: Chemoattraction of neutrophils about monocytes is mediated by the generation of NAP-2," J. Leuk. Biol. 72:175-182, 2002.
        Previously submitted to the Journal of Cell Biology, 2000.
      - Articles 144b, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Articles 145, 2003 (Box 32, Folder 3)
        Malawista, S.E., de Boisfleury Chevance, A., Brown, E.J., Boxer, L.J., and Law, S.K.A. "Chemotaxis of non-compressed blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes from an adolescent with severe Leukocyte Adhesion Deficiency," Amer J Hematol 73:115-120, 2003.
      - Articles 147, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        Montgomery, R.R., Lusitani, D.D., de Boisfleury Chevance, A., Malawista, S.E., "Tick saliva reduces adherence and area of human neutrophil," Infect Immun 72:2989-2994, 2004.
      - Articles 148, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 5)
        Rollet-Labelle, E., Marois, S., Barbeau, K., Malawista, S.E., and Naccache, P.H., "Recruitment of the cross-linked opsonic receptor CD32A (FcgammaRIIA) to high density detergent resistant membrane domains in human neutrophils," Biochem J 381:919-928, 2004.
      - Articles 152, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E. and de Boisfleury Chevance, A., "Phagocytic function of human blood polymorphonuclear leukocytes in the presence of carrageenan, a potential vaginal microbicide," Inflammation 30(5):131-5, 2007.
      - Articles 155, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 7)
        Malawista, S.E., de Boisfleury Chevance, A, Van Damme J., and Serhan, C.N., "Tonic inhibition of chemotaxis in human plasma," Proc Nat Acad Sci USA 105:17949-17954, 2008.
      - "Inflammatory gout: observations over a half-century", 2011 (Box 32, Folder 8)
        Malawista, S.E., de Boisfleury, A.C., Naccacche, P.H., "Inflammatory gout: observations over a half-century," FASEB J. 2011 Dec;25(12):4073-8. This published article did not appear in Malawista's CV. The CV, though dated 2012, was not up to date.
  - Reviews, Subseries 2
    This is a category in Malawista's CV for published articles that are not original research, but rather summarize what is known on a topic. Under reviews are the many chapters Malawista wrote for textbooks. Folders are keyed to the numbering in Malawista's 2012 CV. See Box 1, Folder 1, or version of CV attached to this collection.
    - 1960s
      - Reviews 1R, 1965? (Box 33, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E., Howell, R.R. and Seegmiller, J.E., "Colchicina en aguda artritis gotosa: Estudios clinicos y metabolicos," Revista Medica de Chile [1965?]. Publication of "Colchicine in Acute Gouty Arthritis: Clinical and Metabolic Studies," translated into Spanish. This paper was presented by Malawista at the Third Pan American Congress on Rheumatic Diseases, Santiago Chile, in October 1963.
        Folder contains correspondence, 1963-1965, review, drafts, notes, and photographs. See Box 55, Folder 4 for more information on the Congress.
      - Reviews 3R, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E. "The role of sodium urate crystals in the pathogenesis of acute gouty arthritis," Proceedings of the Symposium on Gout, XIth International Congress of Rheumatology, Mar del Plata, Argentina, December, l965.
        Correspondence, 1965, and copy of talk.
      - Reviews 4R, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 3)
        Malawista, S.E. "Colchicine: A common mechanism for its antiinflammatory and antimitotic effects," Arthritis Rheum. ll: l9l, l968.
        Correspondence, 1966-1967, drafts, notes.
    - 1970s
      - Reviews 10R, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Reviews 12R, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E. "Microtubules and the mobilization of lysosomes in phagocytizing human leukocytes. In: Conference on the Biology of Cytoplasmic Microtubules. Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 253:738, l975.
      - Reviews 13R, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E. "Microtubules and the movement of melanin granules in frog dermal melanocytes," In: Conference on the Biology of Cytoplasmic Microtubules. Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 253:702-710, l975.
        Correspondence, 1974-1976, drafts, photographs, NYAS conference program, notes.
      - Reviews 14R, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 7)
        Malawista, S.E. "The action of colchicine in acute gouty arthritis," In: Proceedings of the l974 Conference on Purine Metabolism and Gout. Arthritis Rheum. l8:835, l975 (Suppl.) Correspondence, 1974-1975, drafts, notes, photographs.
      - Reviews 15R, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 8)
        Malawista, S.E. "Effects of colchicine and vinblastine on the mobilization of lysosomes in phagocytizing human leukocytes." In: Microtubules and Microtubule Inhibitors, M. Borgers and M. DeBrabender, eds. North Holland/American Elsevier, Amsterdam, l975, pp. l99-206
      - Reviews 17R, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 9)
        Steere, A.C., Hardin, J.A. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme arthritis: A new clinical entity," Hospital Practice l3: l43-l58, l978.
      - Reviews 18R, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 10)
        Steere, A.C., Hardin, J.A. and Malawista, S.E. "Erythema chronicum migrans and Lyme arthritis: Related problems recently recognized in Connecticut," Connecticut Medicine 42:353-357, l978.
      - Reviews 19R, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 11)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Viral Arthritis," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, 9th Edition, D.J. McCarty, ed. Lea and Febiger, Philadelphia, l979, pp. l39l-l407.
    - 1980s
      - Reviews 20R, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E. and deBoisfleury-Chevance, A. "Leukocytes (the engine of cellular locomotion) [cytoplast work reproduced]," in: Stossel, T.P. "How Cells Crawl," Amer. Scientist 78:408-423, 1990.
      - Reviews 21R, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)